legislation.gov.au 2009-06-13

# ComLaw - Site privacy notice

## Privacy Statement

* * *

The Attorney-General's Department is subject to the [_Privacy Act 1988_](http://www.comlaw.gov.au/comlaw/management.nsf/lookupindexpagesbyid/IP200401860?OpenDocument) which requires that we comply with the [Information Privacy Principles](http://www.privacy.gov.au/publications/ipps.html) (IPPs) set out in the Act. The IPPs set out how Australian Government agencies should collect, use, store and disclose personal information and how individuals can access records containing their personal information.

The personal information handling practices of the Attorney-General’s Department are detailed in the annual [Personal Information Digest](http://www.ag.gov.au/www/agd/rwpattach.nsf/VAP/\(878CAEAF8D7CA41B4CD31727CCC28450\)~Attorney-General_s+Department+PID+2006x.pdf/$file/Attorney-General_s+Department+PID+2006x.pdf). This sets out the kind of personal information collected or held by the Department, what it is used for, to whom it is disclosed and how access to the information can be arranged. 

General enquiries about the Department's compliance with the IPPs can be made to the Department's Privacy Contact Officer. Any complaints about the Department's personal information handling practices can be made to the Privacy Contact Officer or to the Privacy Commissioner. The Privacy Contact Officer can be contacted on (02) 6250 6211 or by writing to the Department.

General information about the Privacy Act and IPPs can be found on the [Office of the Privacy Commissioner's website](http://www.privacy.gov.au/).

#### About this website

The Attorney-General's Department (which owns ComLaw) is committed to protecting privacy in accordance with the Guidelines for Federal and ACT Government World Wide Websites issued by the Office of the Privacy Commissioner.

While every effort is made to secure information transmitted to this site over the internet, there is a possibility that this information could be accessed by a third party while in transit.

#### Information logged

When you visit this site, our server logs the following information: 

  * the type of browser and operating system you are using 
  * your top level domain name (for example .com, .gov, .au, .uk) 
  * the address of the referring site (for example, the previous site that you visited) 
  * your server's IP address (a number which is unique to the machine through which you are connected to the Internet: usually one of your service provider's machines) 
  * the date and time of your visit, and 
  * the address of the pages accessed and the documents downloaded. 

This information is used only for statistical analysis and systems administration purposes. No attempt is made to identify users or their browsing activities, except in the unlikely event of an investigation by a law enforcement agency.

#### Electronic mail addresses

We will only record your e-mail address if you send us a message. It will only be used for the purpose for which you provide it. In particular, we will not add it to a mailing list unless you request that this be done or disclose it without your consent.

#### Subscriptions

Some pages of this internet site provide the facility for users to subscribe to email mailing lists. To subscribe to these services users need to provide a valid email address. These email addresses will only be used for the purpose for which you have provided them. Email mailing list addresses are stored on a separate server and can only be accessed by authorised Attorney-General's Department staff.

#### Cookies

A cookie is an electronic token that is passed to your browser which passes it back to the server whenever a page is sent to you.

Our server generates one cookie which is used to keep track of the pages you have accessed while using our serv er. The c ookie allows you to page back and forwards through the web site and return to page s you have already visited. The cookie exists only for the time you are accessing our server. 

#### Searches

Search terms you enter when using our search engine are collected, but are not associated with any other information that we collect. We use these search terms to ascertain what people are looking for at our site, and to improve the services that we provide. 

#### Links to other sites

This site contains links to other sites. The Attorney-General's Department is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these sites.
